<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Going Minimal - The Joy of Less </title>
    <link>/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Going Minimal - The Joy of Less </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 08:13:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>code</title>
      <link>/code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 08:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/code/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 08:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i work long hours</title>
      <link>blog/i-work-long-hours/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 08:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>blog/i-work-long-hours/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I work long hours. I travel a lot. Over a hundred flights a year. Many thousands of miles. I get paid fairly, I love my job. I’ve a nice house, amazing wife, two wonderful daughters and a pooch called Bud. Life’s pretty sweet – I’m immensely grateful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m not happy. Slowly, insidiously, things for which I attach no value have been eating more and more of my time – my only real precious resource.
At the last count over 2016, my wife and I spend around 45 hours a week using our phones (thank you Moment). Forty five hours a week. It’s outrageous. That’s 98 days a year of screen time. And that doesn’t even count the time I spend on the computer, iPad and watching television. 20% of our waking time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And don’t think we’re far from the norm. In fact we’re slightly below the global average.
Not only that, but our beautiful house is full of stuff that we have accumulated over time a significant proportion of which doesn’t make our lives better – but does take our time to manage. There are a few stick out things – the french dresser our friends gave us as our wedding present, the wood burning stove, the coffee machine and the food mixer for which Hels, the Skids and I lovingly prepare baked goodies. The photographs. The paintings. A writing desk owned by my Gramps. A beautiful dining table given to us by my parents. I hugely appreciate these things and others. But there’s so much that we don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sauce pan from my first house, my collection of smelly shirts – four, yes four Leprechaun outfits. Soiled. My collection of laptops, 14 raspberry pi’s, some outdated electronics. That old stereo from school that doesn’t even work.
So 2017 is it. I’m parting ways with my smartphone, and resurrecting my classic Nokia c9, my junk is being pawned off or binned. My time is being reclaimed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m making a bit of kit called “Tellytime” that monitors both how much time we spend as a family in front of the telly, and also does some sentiment analysis to see if it actually makes us smile – its a fun little project with a real purpose behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the stuff – cupboard by cupboard I&amp;rsquo;m asking myself – not shall I throw this away, but does this make my life valuable. If not, and it may be if use to others, we’re giving away to charity. If it’s rubbish, its going in the bin.
It not so easy with the kids stuff – so we’re letting them choose. They’ve had some amazing presents over the last few weeks – for the ones they don’t use very often – we’ve already asked them if they would rather keep it, or give it to someone who doesn’t have toys to play with – they like giving gifts as much as receiving them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the time I reclaim from Facebook, I’m going to spend it in real life with my family and friends. Real conversations. Dinner. Pints. No fucking status updates of feel good videos or Jeremy Corbyn shares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its time I started getting my life, health and wealth back and doing more with my time. No more crap. No more Facebook. No more emptying the garage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I know, if you’ve read this far, you’re thinking – what a grumpy git I am. I’m not, I’ve just realised that the things that make me most happy in life – time with my family and friends – are being eroded by things, that whilst somewhat compulsive – don’t actually matter to me in the slightest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It time to simplify. Fancy joining me?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>